Jean-Charles Quillet

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMING

13, rue du clos romain, 35120 Dol-de-Bretagne, FRANCE

🛮 (+33) 6-65-13-50-75 | 🗷 jeancharles.quillet@gmail.com | 🔏 jeancharles.quillet.org | 🖸 jecaro | 🛅 jeancharlesquillet

Summary.

I am a software developer with a large experience in very diverse fields. I have worked as a backend developer, have written desktop applications, simulation software as well as network servers.

I have had the chance to work with low-level object-oriented programming such as C++ which I have used professionally for more than ten years, and also with very high-level functional programming languages such as Haskell. These different approaches give me a good comprehension of the mechanisms at work in software development, always driven by the goal of developing correct, safe, and robust software.

Skills

Main skills Architecture and software design

Functional and object oriented programming Networking / Linux systems administration Geographic Information Systems

Geometry and 3D rendering

Programming Haskell, Rust, Elm, C/C++, Python, Bash **Development tools** Nix, Make, Git, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker

Scientific tools Matlab, Octave, gnuplot

Operating systems Windows, Linux (NixOS, ArchLinux, Ubuntu, CentOS, Debian) **Languages** French: mother tongue, English: fluent, Spanish: beginner

Experience _____

BACKEND DEVELOPER

Tiko Zürich, Switzerland / Remote

Since 01/2024

• Interface between IoT devices and backend services

• Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, nix, K8s, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Kafka, MQTT

SecucloudHamburg, Germany / Remote

 CLOUD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER
 11/2020 - 11/2023

• Develop cloud network security software

• Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, JavaScript, nix, MySQL, Ansible, Redis, Clickhouse

Epitech Rennes, France

FUNCTIONAL PROGRAMMING TEACHER

09/2021 - 06/2023 (part time)

- Supported the students with their Haskell projects (Arithmetic expression evaluator, List interpretor, image compression algorithm ...)
- · Technical environment: Linux, Haskell, nix

Scalian Rennes, France

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER FOR A SUBCONTRACTOR COMPANY

04/2007 - 11/2020

- Developed simulation software in the department Simulation, HPC and Virtual Reality
- Architecture and technical lead
- Technical documentation writing
- Clients: french MoD, ONERA, CEA, CNES, IRSN
- Technical environment: Windows/Linux, C++, Python, Matlab, Qt, openscenegraph, gdal

LaBRI Analysis and indexing video team (University lab)

Bordeaux, France

07/2006 - 08/2006

- Prepared the video indexing contests TRECVID and ARGOS
- System administration

RESEARCH ENGINEER

• Technical environment: Linux, C/C++, XML, Perl, Bash

1

INRIA IPARLA team (French IT lab)

Bordeaux, France

RESEARCH ENGINEER 09/2004 – 04/2006

- Visualization of city models on mobile devices though non-photorealistic rendering
- Wrote and presented a scientific paper to the Web3D 2006 conference in Washington
- Technical environment: Linux, Windows, Windows Mobile, C/C++, Bash, Perl, VRML97, X3D

Keyghost Christchurch, New-Zealand

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

04/2003 - 12/2003

- · Developed security software
- Technical environment: Windows, Delphi, C/C++, Octave

Visualpix Bordeaux, France

INTERNSHIP FOLLOWED BY A SOFTWARE ENGINEER CONTRACT

04/2002 - 12/2002

- Improved a video compression codec
- Technical environment: Linux, C

Glisshouse Marseille, France

BACKEND DEVELOPER, SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

07/2000 - 03/2001

- Web: Maintained an online shop, developed a CMS
- System administration: Installed, setup and maintained the LAN (router, DNS, firewall, proxy, backup management, file server, print server)
- Technical environment: Linux, Php, MySQL, Apache, Samba, cron

Education

2001 - 2002	DESS Multimedia and Information Technology,	Bordeaux university
	image synthesis and analysis, 3D geometry and rendering, sound, video	
1999 - 2000	Master in computer science, image synthesis and analysis	Poitiers university
1998 - 1999	B.S. in computer science	Limoges university
1996 - 1997	DEUG computer science and mathematics	Limoges university
1995 - 1996	Baccalauréat Science	Lycée Jean Giraudoux, Châteauroux

Extracurricular Activity

Sports Rock climbing, bike commuting, surf, trekking

Culture Literature (classical, travel, adventure), cinema, attending rock concerts, guitar playing

Community commitments Member of the direction comity of the rock climbing club of Rennes (2012 to 2016)

Volunteered at concert venues of Rennes: Antipode (2011 to 2015), le Jardin Moderne (2009 to 2010)

Volunteered to the music festivals Epipapu (2009, 2010) and la Route du Rock (2008 - 2018)

Travel New-Zealand, Australia, USA, Canada, Malaysia, Bali, Bolivia, Iceland, Norway, Scotland, Faroe Islands